Jacob Blakely | Senior Full Stack Software Engineer

✓ jacobmblakely@gmail.com ♀ codekirei in jacob-blakely

I specialize in making complex things simple. I have years of experience in crafting and delivering elegant software solutions across the entire stack, with a focus on the web and the command line, and have experience both leading and contributing to remote software teams to ship products to millions of users. Comfortable in customer-facing roles. Excellent communicator.

SKILLS -

Typescript, Node.js, Python, Lua, Go, CSS, SQL, Shell Languages

Frameworks React, Redux, Jest, Next.js, Django, REST Framework, Kubernetes

Other API Design and Development, Webhooks, Technical Documentation, AWS.

GraphQL, Database Architecture, Linux Administration, Microservices, Git, Open Source Development, Customer Support, Responsive Design, CI/CD

EXPERIENCE -

Blakely Real Estate | Co-Owner and Chief Technologist

2022 - 2023

- Introduced systems automation to significantly reduce operational overhead
- Architected data migrations between disparate backend platforms
- Designed and implemented new marketing channels to diversify client pipelines
- Attained license to practice real estate in state of Oregon

Zapier | Senior Full Stack Software Engineer

2016 - 2022

- Created and maintained internal Chrome extension that leveraged internal APIs to enable efficient customer support; entire support team relied on this tool to do their work
- Co-created critical webhook ingestion service that reliably handles tens of millions of daily requests; includes smart journaling system to mitigate data loss
- Co-lead prototyping team that developed visionary product prototypes; many features directly influenced new products that drive millions in ARR, like the visual editor
- Embedded in core frontend team to refactor critical legacy components; significantly reduced frontend build complexity
- Created internal blog-focused CMS that was one of three pillars of internal communication at company and was used regularly by every employee
- Participated in hiring panels for 10+ roles as engineering team scaled from 15 to 100+
- Mentored 5+ early-stage engineers one-on-one who went on to be key contributors
- Promoted to senior in January of 2021

Code Kirei LLC | Freelance Engineer and Consultant

2014 - Present

Providing web-focused technology consulting and software development services.

Translations.com | Client Services

2012 - 2013

- Account manager for clients worth over a million dollars in annual revenue
- First point of contact for said clients for new project requisition and project support
- Oversaw full project lifecycle and delivery via effective collaboration with internal teams

EDUCATION —

University of Oregon, Clark Honors College

2007 - 2012

Bachelor of Arts, Cum Laude

Major Business Administration

ConcentrationEntrepreneurshipMinorsJapanese, Economics